https://ncfi.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Home About NCFI
Overview Board & Committees Next Generation NCFI
About IICN Regions
Africa Caribbean and North America Europe Latin America Pacific And East Asia South Asia and Middle East
About IICN Regions
Africa Caribbean and North America Europe Latin America Pacific And East Asia South Asia and Middle East
Events Resources
Resources & Publications Blog
Courses Volunteering Membership
Privacy Policy
This policy adopted in 2018, covers all aspects of our collection, use and protection of information.
Nurses Christian Fellowship International (NCFI) is a non-profit, tax-exempt organization. Maintenance of its tax-exempt status is important for its continued financial stability and for public support. Therefore, the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) as well as state regulatory and tax officials view the operations of NCFI as a public trust, which is subject to scrutiny by and accountable to such governmental authorities as well as to members of the public. Consequently, there exists between NCFI and its board, officers, employees, volunteers, and the public, a fiduciary duty, which carries with it a broad and unbending duty of loyalty and fidelity. The board, officers, employees and volunteers have the responsibility of administering the affairs of NCFI honestly and prudently, and of exercising their best care, skill and judgment for the sole benefit of NCFI. Those persons shall exercise the utmost good faith in all transactions involved in their duties, and they shall not use their positions with NCFI or knowledge gained therefrom for their personal benefit. The interests of the organization must be the first priority in all decisions and actions. NCFI standard of privacy All staff, members and others acting as volunteers, contractors and suppliers working for or on behalf of NCFI must comply with the NCFI Policy of Privacy when handling personal information of members, donors, staff or volunteers. All those working with personal information in NCFI are required to read this document and by signing it, they confirm that they will keep these practices. Personal information is defined as “data that identifies an individual or enables an individual to be identified”. This includes all data held by NCFI databases whether held in electronic or printed form. NCFI is committed to protect privacy related to all personal information. NCFI will not share any such personal information with other organizations for any purpose without explicit permission from the person whose data is being shared. Collection and Use of Information NCFI may collect information such as postal and email addresses in the process of providing best service to people. Such information can be gathered in relation to NCFI conferences and congresses, courses run by or in collaboration with NCFI, subscriptions for NCFI services, and contacts through NCFI website. NCFI will only use such information to plan our activities, to process requests, and to send information that we see as beneficial in serving nurses around the world. Data generated before, during, and after NCFI congresses shall be used solely for the work of NCFI. NCFI will not send unsolicited emails on behalf of a third party to our members. Some or all of the following types of data, where necessary for the work of NCFI, may be collected and processed:
Names, titles, photographs; Contact details such as telephone numbers, addresses and email addresses; Where they are relevant to our work, or where you provide them to us, we may process demographic information such as gender, age, date of birth, education/work histories and academic/professional qualifications. Where you make donations or pay for activities, we use bank account numbers, payment card numbers and payment/transaction identifiers. Where you provide the information, we may collect sensitive personal data, including, your religious beliefs or your physical or mental health.
All NCFI information and NCFI subscriptions sent out to groups by email shall be sent with email addresses as Bcc so all identities are hidden. NCFI will consider these questions to help judge which information should be processed or kept.
Do we really need this information about an individual? Do we know what we are going to use it for? Do the people whose information we hold know that we have got it, and are they likely to understand what it will be used for? If we are asked to pass on personal information, would the people about whom we hold information expect me to do this? Are we satisfied that the information is being held securely, whether it is on paper or on computer? Is the NCFI website secure? Is access to personal information limited to those with a strict need to know? Are we sure that personal information is accurate and up to date? Do we delete or destroy personal information as soon as we have no more need for it?
Protection of Information NCFI uses the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information over the web, along with other security measures. We ensure that access to personal data is restricted only to those staff members or volunteers whole roles require such access. How do we process personal data? NCFI complies with its obligations under GDPR in the European Union and similar requirements in other jurisdictions by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data. We only retain data that is current and destroy any out of date data. We use your personal data for the following purposes:
To keep you up to date on news and stories about our mission and work;  To administer membership records; To ask for financial and non-financial support, such as volunteering or prayer; To manage our employees and volunteers; To maintain our own accounts and records; To process purchases of goods and services; To process registrations for events; To process any donations you give us; To inform you of events and activities; To operate NCFI’s websites and deliver the services that individuals have  requested; To provide a personalised service such as customised website content or personalised   emails; To classify supporters by location.  To contact individuals via surveys to conduct research about their opinions.
Legal Duty We may need to pass on information if required by law or by a regulatory body. For example, an IRS audit or if asked for details by a law enforcement agency. Your rights and your personal data Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR or equivalent legislation, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:-
The right to request a copy of your personal data which NCFI holds about you;  The right to request that NCFI corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date; The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for NCFI to retain such data; The right to withdraw your consent from processing at any time;  The right to object to the processing of personal data where processing is based on legitimate interests; The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office or the equivalent in your country.
Links NCFI’s websites and communications may contain links to other websites. The privacy and data collection practices on linked websites are separate from NCFI and are not covered by this privacy statement. Changing Your Information and Mailing Preferences Private information is used to send information to individuals about NCFI. Updates, changes, or a request to delete all personal information can be sent to information@ncfi.org – NCFI will respond promptly to such requests. Changes to this Statement NCFI reserves the right to make changes to this privacy statement at any time. The current NCFI policy of privacy is published on the NCFI website at www.ncfi.org. Contacting NCFI For complaints of all kinds related to this privacy statement, please contact information@ncfi.org and NCFI will be happy to respond to such concerns. Adopted October 2018 by the NCFI Executive Committee Tove GiskePresident, NCFI International Board This policy will be reviewed every 2 years. This policy will be distributed to every National Nurses Christian Fellowships (NNCFs) and NCF.
Sections
Search
Latest Blog Post
The Most Difficult Year for Nursing
by Martha Fernández Moyano (Argentina) “For I will satisfy the weary soul, and satisfy every sorrowful soul” Jeremiah 31:25 None of us doubt that this
Read More »
NCFI Regions
Africa Caribbean and North America Europe Latin America Pacific And East Asia South Asia and Middle East
Menu
Africa Caribbean and North America Europe Latin America Pacific And East Asia South Asia and Middle East
Donate Today
NCFI aims to extend God’s kingdom through nurses worldwide. We’d love for you to join with us – in prayer, in action and in giving.Christian nurses in over thirty nations are involved in caring, teaching, training and communicating the good news of Jesus in deed and word. Help today!
Donate
Make Contact
Privacy Policy
NCFI Connections
Send NCFI a request to receive receive the newsletter by email.  If you would like to submit an article about national NCF or NCFI regional activities please indicate below.
